OLGA BOLSHCHIKOVA

Portfolio website: http://bolshchikova.com
760 North 7th St., San Jose, CA 95112
(347) 873-7216 • olga.bolshchikova@gmail.com
Fully Work Authorized • No Visa Sponsorship Required

SUMMARY:

Analytical, driven, and creative visual designer with 10+ years of experience enhancing brands through print and web design and production roles; able to lead design projects and service business needs through production, design, and formatting of creative materials

KEY SKILLS:

- Experience in design and layout of a variety of print and web assets, preparing files for print, and responsive design
- Expertise in composition, typography, hierarchy of messaging, image manipulation, masking, color correction, and digital photo retouching using Photoshop
- Skilled at UX/UI design for websites, landing pages, e-commerce, and mobile apps
- Proficient at Adobe Creative Suite (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat Pro, Illustrator), Adobe Muse, Sketch3, CorelDraw, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Keynote on both Mac and Windows
- Knowledge of HTML5, CSS3; familiar with WordPress and Dreamweaver
- Prototyping with Balsamiq, Draw.io, and InVision
- Ability to complete a high volume of projects on time and on budget, work well in a deadline-driven environment with a keen eye for detail
- Fluent in English and Russian

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Graphic Designer/Production Artist Blue Apple Design, Menlo Park, CA

4/2016 - Present

3/2015 - 3/2016

Full service design studio specializing in user experience, web design and visual identity

• Designed and laid out 10+ interactive e-books and whitepapers by following corporate brand identity and visual guidelines (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator) under tight deadlines

Graphic Designer

Safe Drive Systems, New York, NY

Developer and distributor of advanced radar and camera-based collision avoidance systems

- Designed user-centered landing pages, banner ads, e-brochures, and flyers from design concept to completion utilizing InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat, and Illustrator; resulted in 18% increase in product sales
- Created animated presentations in Keynote and PowerPoint for potential car buyers in 60+ dealerships and product promotion on company website
- Redesigned website blog for better user interaction and SEO optimization; blog traffic increased by over 50%
- Designed and presented 2-3 advertising mockups per project (landing page, e-brochure, flyer) in close collaboration with marketing team for discussion at stakeholder briefings to assist brand strategy development; created final mockups based on feedback for approval and implementation

Graphic Designer/Production Artist

9/2014 - 8/2015

IMR, New York, NY

Public policy think-tank that promotes social, economic, and institutional development in Russia

- Supervised redesign, layout, and production of "IMR Review," the quarterly corporate magazine with circulation of 1K; implemented image manipulations, color correction, photo retouching, and vector graphics to improve visual perception and quality of the magazine
- Designed, laid out, and produced multipage journalistic reports utilizing Adobe Creative Suite, from initial concept through prepress under tight deadlines with no errors; successfully presented at a conference in Washington, D.C., and at a political discussion forum in NYC

12/2000 - 5/2014

Integral LLC, Yekaterinburg, Russia

Publishing house and advertising agency; partner of Pfizer, Nestle, Royal Canin, and Merial

- Designed, laid out, and produced creative materials including ads, posters, newsletters, printed brochures, booklets (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat) with vector diagrams and infographics (Illustrator), digital banners, and presentations (PowerPoint) to meet the requirements of local and national companies
- Supervised design, layout and production of 5 monthly scientific-practical magazines and 3 monthly newspapers with a circulation of 15K+ and distributed in 46 regions of Russia
- Collaborated with scientific and manufacturing companies to create or redesign brand identity (logos, business cards, stationery) to be more up-to-date or appeal more to their target audience
- Collaborated with marketing team and software engineers to redesign client websites (Photoshop, HTML/CSS, WordPress) to provide more efficient, satisfying experience for users through simple and intuitive interface, resulting in 15-20% increase in client sales
- Reduced ~30% of client printing costs by interviewing and selecting the best offset/digital print vendor

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science (BS), Engineering Physics Ural Polytechnic Institute (Ural Federal University), Yekaterinburg, Russia Ranked 7th best Russian university by Webometrics Ranking of World Universities

PRPOFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT:

- **Design and Make Infographics** (project-centered online course), Coursera, 7–8/2016
- **UX/UI Design Course**, Bloc Inc., 8–12/2015
- **Human-Computer Interaction** (online course) Coursera, 7–8/2014
- HTML & CSS (online course), Codecademy, 4-5/2013